Ted Hughes papers, 1940-1999
Emory University
- Writings by Ted Hughes, circa 1949-1990, Series 2; Boxes 57-86; OP2-58a; 105-107; OBV1
  - Scripts and librettos, Subseries 2.5; Boxes 116-122
    - Crow from the Life and Songs of the Crow, October 1970 (Box 122, Folder 23)
    - "Crossing the Water by Sylvia Plath," MS and TS, July 1971 (Box 122, Folder 24)
    - "Yehuda Amichai," Radio 3, 26 May 1976 [with introduction by Ted Hughes] (Box 122, Folder 25)
    - "Magic Phrase," MS, potential BBC program [See also Subseries 2.3: "Three Things Time Will Not Spare"] (Box 122, Folder 26)
    - Unidentified BBC script, p. 9-17 (Box 122, Folder 27)
  - Children's writings, 1961-1997, Subseries 2.6; Boxes 123-130; OP47-57
    The subseries consists materials relating to Hughes's childrens collected works from 1961-1997. Materials relating to his published collections may include drafts of the book's table of contents, manuscript and typescript poems, complete typescripts, and proofs. The manuscripts and typescripts of individual poems have been arranged alphabetically by the poem's title, with unpublished material at the end of the subseries. If a poem was known by more than one title, the variant title(s) have been provided in brackets. If a poem was made up of, or included, other poems this is also indicated in brackets, thus [includes... .]. Because of Hughes' propensity to reuse paper, cross-references are used to note locations of related materials in other parts of the collection.
    - Meet My Folks (1961)
    - "Fairy Godmother," MS (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - "My Aunt Flo," MS (Box 123, Folder 2)
    - "My Grandpa," TS [See Subseries 2.3: "Miscellaneous Notes"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "My Granny," MS and TS (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - "My Own True Family," MS (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - "My Uncle Mick," MS (Box 123, Folder 5)
    - Meet My Folks, Drafts of unpublished poems (Box 123, Folder 6)
    - Meet My Folks, Page proof (Box 123, Folder 7)
    - Meet My Folks, Corrected page proofs (Box 123, Folder 8)
    - Meet My Folks, Photocopy of page proofs (Box 123, Folder 9)
    - Meet My Folks, Galley proofs (Box OP47)
    - How the Whale Became (1963)
    - "How the Monkey Became," not published [See Subseries 2.2: Recklings, "The Toughest"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - How the Whale Became, TS (Box 123, Folder 10)
    - How the Whale Became, Page proofs (Box 123, Folder 11)
    - How the Whale Became, Bound page proofs (Box 123, Folder 12)
    - How the Whale Became, Corrected bound page proofs (Box 123, Folder 13)
    - How the Whale Became, Galley (Box 123, Folder 14)
    - The Earth-Owl and Other Moon-People (1963)
    - "The Adaptable Mountain Dugong," MS and TS (Box 123, Folder 15)
    - "The Armies of the Moon," MS and TS (Box 123, Folder 16)
    - "The Burrow Wolf," MS and TS (Box 123, Folder 17)
    - "Cactus-Sickness," MS and TS [variant title: "Galloping Cactus"] (Box 123, Folder 18)
    - "Crab Grass," MS and TS (Box 123, Folder 19)
    - "The Dracula Vine," MS and TS (Box 123, Folder 20)
    - "The Earth-Owl," MS and TS (Box 123, Folder 21)
    - "Foxgloves," TS [See also Subseries 2.6: Earth-Owl and Other Moon People, "Moon Dog-Daisies" and "Moon Tulips"] (Box 123, Folder 22)
    - "Moon-Cabbage," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Recklings, "Don Giovanni and Subseries 2.6: Earth-Owl and Other Moon People, "The Snail of the Moon"] (Box 123, Folder 23)
    - "Moon-Cloud Gripe," MS (Box 123, Folder 24)
    - "Moon Dog-Daisies," MS and TS (Box 123, Folder 25)
    - "Moon-Freaks," MS (Box 123, Folder 26)
    - "Moon-hops," MS and TS ) [See Subseries 2.6: Earth-Owl and Other Moon People, "Moon dog-Daisies"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Moon-Horrors," MS and TS (Box 123, Folder 27)
    - "A Moon Man Hunt," MS and TS (Box 123, Folder 28)
    - "Moon-Nasturtiums," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.6: Earth-Owl and Other Moon People, "Moon dog-Daisies"] (Box 123, Folder 29)
    - "Moon Roses," MS and TS [variant title: "Moon-blooms"] [See also Subseries 2.6: Earth-Owl and Other Moon People, "Moon Dog-Daisies"] (Box 123, Folder 30)
    - "Moon Transport," MS and TS (Box 123, Folder 31)
    - "Moon Tulips," MS and TS (Box 123, Folder 32)
    - "Music on the Moon," MS and TS (Box 123, Folder 33)
    - "The Silent Eye," MS and TS [variant title: "The Flying Eye] (Box 123, Folder 34)
    - "The Snail of the Moon," MS and TS (Box 123, Folder 35)
    - "Tree-Disease," MS and TS (Box 123, Folder 36)
    - Earth Owl and other Moon People, TS (Box 123, Folder 37)
    - Earth Owl and other Moon People, Page proofs (Box 123, Folder 38)
    - Nessie the Mannerless Monster (1964)
    - Nessie the Mannerless Monster, Cover for paperback edition (Box 123, Folder 39)
    - Nessie the Mannerless Monster, MS [See also Subseries 2.6: Under the North Star, "The Eagle" and Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box 123, Folder 40)
    - Nessie the Mannerless Monster, Page proofs for paperback edition (Box 123, Folder 41)
    - Nessie the Mannerless Monster, Text proof and galley proof, 1st paperback edition (1992) (Box OP48)
    - Animal Poems (1967)
    - "Lineage," MS (Box 123, Folder 42)
    - Five Autumn Songs for Children's Voices (1968)
    - "The Seven Sorrows of Autumn," MS [See Subseries 2.2: Season Songs, Possible outlines, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - Five Autumn Songs for Children's Voices, Printed version with annotations (Box 123, Folder 43)
    - The Iron Man (1968)
    - The Iron Man, MS (Box 123, Folder 44)
    - The Iron Man, TS (Box 123, Folder 45)
    - The Iron Man, Corrected page proofs (Box 123, Folder 46)
    - The Iron Man, Page proofs (Box 123, Folder 47)
    - The Iron Man, Proofs of illustrations (Box 124, Folder 1)
    - Earth-Moon (1976)
    - Notebook of MS poems (Box 124, Folder 2)
    - "Earth Moon," TS (Box 124, Folder 3)
    - "The Moon Bull," TS (Box 124, Folder 4)
    - "Moon Clock," TS (Box 124, Folder 5)
    - "The Moon-Haggis," TS (Box 124, Folder 6)
    - "A Moon-Hare," TS (Box 124, Folder 7)
    - "Moon Heads," TS (Box 124, Folder 8)
    - "Moon Heyena," TS (Box 124, Folder 9)
    - "A Moon-Lily," TS (Box 124, Folder 10)
    - "The Moon-Mare" [See also Subseries 2.2: River, "After Moonless Midnight"] (Box 124, Folder 11)
    - "Moon Marriage," TS (Box 124, Folder 12)
    - "Moon Mirror," TS (Box 124, Folder 13)
    - "The Moon Mourner," TS (Box 124, Folder 14)
    - "The Moon-Oak," TS (Box 124, Folder 15)
    - "Moon Ravens," TS (Box 124, Folder 16)
    - "Moon-Shadow Beggars," MS and TS (Box 124, Folder 17)
    - "Moon-Theatre," TS (Box 124, Folder 18)
    - "Moon Thirst," TS (Box 124, Folder 19)
    - "Moon Thorns," TS (Box 124, Folder 20)
    - "Moon Walkers," TS (Box 124, Folder 21)
    - "Moon Ways," TS (Box 124, Folder 22)
    - "MoonWeapons," TS (Box 124, Folder 23)
    - "Moon-Whales," TS (Box 124, Folder 24)
    - "Moon-Wind," TS (Box 124, Folder 25)
    - "Moon Wings," TS (Box 124, Folder 26)
    - "A Moon-Witch," TS (Box 124, Folder 27)
    - "Moon Witches," TS (Box 124, Folder 28)
    - "Moony Art," TS (Box 124, Folder 29)
    - "Mushrooms on the Moon," TS (Box 124, Folder 30)
    - "Singing on the Moon," TS (Box 124, Folder 31)
    - "Visiting the Moon," TS [variant titles: "Moon-Glimplses," "Just Looking Round," and "Moon-Looking"] (Box 124, Folder 32)
    - Earth-Moon, TS I (Box 124, Folder 33)
    - Earth-Moon, TS II (Box 124, Folder 34)
    - Moon-Whales and Other Moon Poems (1976)
    - Moon-Whales and Other Moon Poems, Various TS pages (Box 124, Folder 35)
    - Moon-Whales and Other Moon Poems, TS I (Box 124, Folder 36)
    - Moon-Whales and Other Moon Poems, TS II (Box 124, Folder 37)
    - Moon-Whales and Other Moon Poems, Page proofs (2) (Box OP49)
    - Moon-Whales and Other Moon Poems, Paperback Proofs (1991) (Box 124, Folder 38)
    - Moon-Bells and Other Poems (1978)
    - "Ants," MS and TS (Box 124, Folder 39)
    - "He Gets Up In Dark Dawn," MS (Box 124, Folder 40)
    - "Horrible Song," MS (Box 124, Folder 41)
    - "Mountain Lion," MS (Box 124, Folder 42)
    - "Nessie," TS (Box 124, Folder 43)
    - "Off Days," MS (Box 124, Folder 44)
    - "The Tigress," MS (Box 124, Folder 45)
    - Pets and Other Poems, TS [transitional title to Moon-Bells and Other Poems] (Box 124, Folder 46)
    - Moon-Bells and Other Poems (1978): Various TS pages (Box 124, 47)
    - Moon-Bells and Other Poems (1978): Page proofs (Box OP50)
    - Moon-Bells and Other Poems (1978): Galley (Box 124, Folder 48)
    - Moon-Bells and Other Poems (1978): Proofs of illustrations (Box 124, Folder 49)
    - Moon-Bells and Other Poems (1978): Cover mock-up (Box 124, Folder 50)
    - The Threshold (1979)
    - The Threshold, MS I (Box 124, Folder 51)
    - The Threshold, MS II (Box 124, Folder 52)
    - The Threshold, MS III (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - The Threshold, TS (Box 125, Folder 2)
    - Under the North Star (1981)
    - Notebook of MS poems (Box 125, Folder 3)
    - "Arctic Fox," TS (Box 125, Folder 4)
    - "Brooktrout," MS and TS (Box 125, Folder 5)
    - "The Eagle," MS and TS (Box 125, Folder 6)
    - "Eagle Owl," MS (Box 125, Folder 7)
    - "An Evening Seal," MS (Box 125, Folder 8)
    - "Goose," MS and TS [variant title: "The Brent Goose"] (Box 125, Folder 9)
    - "Grizzly Bear," MS (Box 125, Folder 10)
    - "Heron," MS (Box 125, Folder 11)
    - "Loon," MS (Box 125, Folder 12)
    - "Lynx," MS and TS (Box 125, Folder 13)
    - "Mooses," MS (Box 125, Folder 14)
    - "Mosquito," MS (Box 125, Folder 15)
    - "The Muskellunge," MS (Box 125, Folder 16)
    - "Musk-Ox," MS and TS (Box 125, Folder 17)
    - "Osprey," MS (Box 125, Folder 18)
    - "Puma," MS (Box 125, Folder 19)
    - "Skunk," MS and TS (Box 125, Folder 20)
    - "The Snow-Show Hare," MS (Box 125, Folder 21)
    - "The Snowy Owl," MS (Box 125, Folder 22)
    - "The Wendigo," MS (Box 125, Folder 23)
    - "Wolf," MS (Box 125, Folder 24)
    - "Wolverine," MS (Box 125, Folder 25)
    - "Woodpecker," MS (Box 125, Folder 26)
    - Under the North Star, TS (Box 125, Folder 27)
    - Under the North Star, TS (photocopy) (Box 125, Folder 28)
    - Under the North Star, Galley proofs (Box 125, Folder 29)
    - What is the Truth? (1984)
    - Notebook of MS poems (Box 125, Folder 30)
    - "Badger," MS and TS (Box 125, Folder 31)
    - "Bat," MS (Box 125, Folder 32)
    - "Bullfinch," MS (Box 125, Folder 33)
    - "Buzzard," MS and TS (Box 125, Folder 34)
    - "Calf," MS (Box 125, Folder 35)
    - "Carp," MS [See Subseries 2.7: Camillo Penneti poems, "Sea Gull"] (Box 125, Folder 36)
    - "Cat," MS (Box 125, Folder 37)
    - "Cows" I [See also Subseries 2.7: Camillo Penneti poems, "Yin"] (Box 125, Folder 38)
    - "Cows" II [See Subseries 2.7: Camillo Penneti poems, "Persian Drawings"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The Dead Vixen," MS and TS (Box 125, Folder 39)
    - "Dog," MS (Box 125, Folder 40)
    - "Donkey," MS (Box 125, Folder 41)
    - "Dream with a Pheasant," TS (Box 125, Folder 42)
    - "Ducks," MS (Box 125, Folder 43)
    - "Fly," MS (Box 125, Folder 44)
    - "The Foal Has Landed," MS and TS [variant titles: " The Foal"] (Box 125, Folder 45)
    - "Fox," MS (Box 125, Folder 46)
    - "Geese," MS and TS (Box 125, Folder 47)
    - "Grass-snake," MS (Box 125, Folder 48)
    - "Hare," MS [See also Subseries 2.6: What is the Truth?, "Pig"] (Box 125, Folder 49)
    - "Hedgehog," MS (Box 125, Folder 50)
    - "Hen," MS (Box 125, Folder 51)
    - "Honey Bee," MS and TS (Box 125, Folder 52)
    - "Horses," MS and TS (Box 125, Folder 53)
    - "Lamb," MS (Box 125, Folder 54)
    - "Mice," TS [See Subseries 2.6: What is the Truth?, "Worms"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Owl," MS [See also Subseries 2.4b: Poetry in the Making, Appendices and misc. poems] (Box 125, Folder 55)
    - "Partridge," MS (Box 125, Folder 56)
    - "Pheasant," MS [See also Subseries 2.2: New Selected Poems, 1957-1994, "Remembering Teheran" and Subseries 2.6: What is the Truth?, "Badger"] (Box 125, Folder 57)
    - "Pig," MS (Box 125, Folder 58)
    - "Pigeons," MS (Box 125, Folder 59)
    - "Rat," MS (Box 125, Folder 60)
    - "Rook," MS and TS (Box 125, Folder 61)
    - "Rooster," MS (Box 125, Folder 62)
    - "Sheep," MS (Box 125, Folder 63)
    - "Sparrow," MS (Box 125, Folder 64)
    - "Swallows," MS (Box 125, Folder 65)
    - "Treecreeper," MS (Box 125, Folder 66)
    - "Weasel," MS (Box 125, Folder 67)
    - "Woodpecker," MS (Box 125, Folder 68)
    - "Worms," MS (Box 126, Folder 1)
    - "Wren," MS (Box 126, Folder 2)
    - What is the Truth?, prose (appeared on pp. 100-103 in published edition) [See Subseries 2.7: Camillo Pennati poems, "Meeting an Extraterrestrial"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - What is the Truth?, Table of contents, Lists of corrections, MS (Box 126, Folder 3)
    - What is the Truth?, TS I [See also Subseries 2.2, Wolfwatching, "Us He Devours," MS] (Box 126, Folder 4)
    - What is the Truth?, TS II (Box 126, Folder 5)
    - What is the Truth?, TS III (Box 126, Folder 6)
    - What is the Truth?, TS IV (Box 126, Folder 7)
    - What is the Truth?, Faxed TS pages (Box 126, Folder 8)
    - What is the Truth?, Photocopy (Box 126, Folder 9)
    - What is the Truth?, Proof with corrections, 22 June 1983 [1] (Box OP51)
    - What is the Truth?, Proof with corrections, 12 July 1983 [4 different copies] (Box OP52)
    - What is the Truth?, Proof with corrections, 22 August 1983 [1] (Box OP53)
    - What is the Truth?, [Final] Proof, 20 October 1983 [1] (Box OP54)
    - Ffangs the Vampire Bat and the Kiss of Truth (1986)
    - Ffangs the Vampire Bat and the Kiss of Truth, Draft MS (Box 126, Folder 10)
    - Ffangs the Vampire Bat and the Kiss of Truth, TS (Box 126, Folder 11)
    - Ffangs the Vampire Bat and the Kiss of Truth, Copy of TS (Box 126, Folder 12)
    - Ffangs the Vampire Bat and the Kiss of Truth, Page proofs (Box 126, Folder 13)
    - Ffangs the Vampire Bat and the Kiss of Truth, Sample settings (Box OP55)
    - Ffangs the Vampire Bat and the Kiss of Truth, Galley proofs (Box OP56)
    - The Cat and the Cuckoo (1987)
    - Notebook of MS poems (Box 127, Folder 1)
    - "Cow," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.4c: Selected Poems by Keith Douglas] (Box 127, Folder 2)
    - "Crow," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.6: The Cat and the Cuckoo, "Cow" and Subseries 2.6: Tales of the Early World, "The Guardian"] (Box 127, Folder 3)
    - "Cuckoo," TS (Box 127, Folder 4)
    - "Dragonfly," TS (Box 127, Folder 5)
    - "Fantails," TS (Box 127, Folder 6)
    - "Goat," MS (Box 127, Folder 7)
    - "Grey Squirrel," TS (Box 127, Folder 8)
    - "Hen," TS [See Subseries 2.2: Wolfwatching, "The Black Rhino," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Mole," MS and TS (Box 127, Folder 9)
    - "Otter," TS [See also Subseries 2.3: "Miscellaneous Notes"] (Box 127, Folder 10)
    - "Owl," TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Wolfwatching, "The Black Rhino," MS] (Box 127, Folder 11)
    - "Pig," MS and TS (Box 127, Folder 12)
    - "Pike," TS (Box 127, Folder 13)
    - "The Red Admiral," MS (Box 127, Folder 14)
    - "Robin," MS and TS (Box 127, Folder 15)
    - "Sparrow," MS (Box 127, Folder 16)
    - "Worm," TS (Box 127, Folder 17)
    - The Cat and the Cuckoo, First proofs (Box 127, Folder 18)
    - The Cat and the Cuckoo, Page proofs (Box 127, Folder 19)
    - The Cat and the Cuckoo, Covers (Box 127, Folder 20)
    - Tales of the Early World (1988)
    - "The Dancers," Notebook of MS and TS (Box 127, Folder 21)
    - "The Guardian," Notebook of MS and TS (Box 127, Folder 22)
    - "The Guardian," photocopy (Box 127, Folder 23)
    - "How Sparrow Saved the Birds," Notebook of MS and TS (Box 127, Folder 24)
    - "The Invaders," Notebook of MS and TS (Box 127, Folder 25)
    - "The Leftovers," Notebook of MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.6, Under the North Star, "Skunk"] (Box 127, Folder 26)
    - "The Making of Parrot," Notebook of MS and TS (Box 127, Folder 27)
    - "The Playmate," Notebook of MS and TS (Box 127, Folder 28)
    - "The Shawl of the Beauty of the World," Notebook of MS and TS (Box 127, Folder 29)
    - "The Snag," Notebook of MS and TS (Box 127, Folder 30)
    - "The Trunk," Notebook of MS and TS (Box 127, Folder 31)
    - Tales of the Early World, Title page (Box 127, Folder 32)
    - Tales of the Early World, Photocopy minus art (Box 127, Folder 33)
    - Tales of the Early World, Page proofs I (Box 127, Folder 34)
    - Tales of the Early World, Page proofs II (Box 127, Folder 35)
    - The Mermaid's Purse (1993)
    - The Mermaid's Purse, Notebook of MS poems, I (Box 128, Folder 1)
    - The Mermaid's Purse, Notebook of MS poems, II (Box 128, Folder 2)
    - The Mermaid's Purse, Photocopies of poems with annotations (Box 128, Folder 3)
    - The Mermaid's Purse, Photocopied draft fragments (Box 128, Folder 4)
    - The Mermaid's Purse, Corrected TS (Box 128, Folder 5)
    - The Mermaid's Purse, Photocopied TS (Box 128, Folder 6)
    - The Mermaid's Purse, Early color proof with corrections [extensive MS revisions to "Ragworm"] (Box OP57)
    - The Mermaid's Purse, Printer's proofs (Box 128, Folder 7)
    - The Iron Woman (1993)
    - Notebooks (4) of MS poems (Box 128, Folder 8)
    - Notebook of MS poems (Box 128, Folder 9)
    - The Iron Woman, MS (Box 128, Folder 10)
    - The Iron Woman, Draft TS (Box 128, Folder 11)
    - The Iron Woman, TS (incomplete) (Box 128, Folder 12)
    - The Iron Woman, Corrected TS (Box 128, Folder 13)
    - The Iron Woman, TS (Box 128, Folder 14)
    - The Iron Woman, Page proofs (Box 128, Folder 15)
    - The Iron Woman, Galley proofs (Box 128, Folder 16)
    - The Dreamfighter and other Creation Tales (1995)
    - "Camel," Notebook of MS (Box 129, Folder 1)
    - "The Dreamfighter" Notebook of MS (Box 129, Folder 2)
    - "The Gambler," Notebook of MS (Box 129, Folder 3)
    - "Goku," Notebook of MS (Box 129, Folder 4)
    - "Gozzie," Notebook of MS (Box 129, Folder 5)
    - "Grizzly Bear and the Human Child" Notebook of MS (Box 129, Folder 6)
    - "How God Got His Golden Head" Notebook of MS (Box 129, Folder 7)
    - "The Last Dinosaurs," Notebook of MS (Box 129, Folder 8)
    - "The Moon and Loopy Downtail," Notebooks of MS (2) (Box 129, Folder 9)
    - "The Screw," MS (Box 129, Folder 10)
    - "The Secret of Man's Wife," MS (Box 129, Folder 11)
    - The Dreamfighter and other Creation Tales, TS w/ unpublished material (Box 129, Folder 12)
    - The Dreamfighter and other Creation Tales, Corrected TS (Box 129, Folder 13)
    - The Dreamfighter and other Creation Tales, Page proofs I (Box 129, Folder 14)
    - The Dreamfighter and other Creation Tales, Page proofs II (Box 129, Folder 15)
    - The Dreamfighter and other Creation Tales, Faxed designs (Box 129, Folder 16)
    - Collected Animal Poems (1995)
    - Tables of contents (Box 129, Folder 17)
    - List of sources (Box 129, Folder 18)
    - List of page proof corrections (Box 129, Folder 19)
    - Vol. 1: The Iron Wolf, "Spider," MS and TS (Box 129, Folder 20)
    - Vol. 1: The Iron Wolf, Page proofs (Box 129, Folder 21)
    - Vol. 1: The Iron Wolf, Page proofs w/ illustrations (Box 129, Folder 22)
    - Vol. 1: The Iron Wolf, Cover (Box 129, Folder 23)
    - Vol. 2: What is the Truth?, Proofs (Box 129, Folder 24)
    - Vol. 2: What is the Truth?, Proofs w/ illustrations (Box 129, Folder 25)
    - Vol. 2: What is the Truth?, Sample cover (Box 130, Folder 1)
    - Vol. 2: What is the Truth?, Cover (Box 130, Folder 2)
    - Vol. 2: What is the Truth?, Photocopy (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - Vol. 3: A March Calf, "The Irish Elk," MS (Box 130, Folder 4)
    - Vol. 3: A March Calf, "Live Skull," TS [variant title: "Trenchford Winter"] (Box 130, Folder 5)
    - Vol. 3: A March Calf, "Tiger," MS and TS (Box 130, Folder 6)
    - Vol. 3: A March Calf, "Very New Foal," MS and TS (Box 130, Folder 7)
    - Vol. 3: A March Calf, "Waterlicked," MS and TS (Box 130, Folder 8)
    - Vol. 3: A March Calf, Page proofs I (Box 130, Folder 9)
    - Vol. 3: A March Calf, Page proofs II (Box 130, Folder 10)
    - Vol. 3: A March Calf, Cover (Box 130, Folder 11)
    - Vol. 4: The Thought Fox, Page proofs I (Box 130, Folder 12)
    - Vol. 4: The Thought Fox, Page proofs II (Box 130, Folder 13)
    - Collected Animal Poems, Illustrations (Box 130, Folder 14)
    - Shaggy and Spotty (1997)
    - Shaggy and Spotty, MS (Inventory from Hughes stated: "as told to Frieda and Nicholas about 1964/5") (Box 130, Folder 15)
    - Uncollected Children's Writings
    - Opening of a children's story about Adam and Eve (Box 130, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified Children's prose ["Once upon a time, the world disappeared," MS] (Box 130, Folder 17)
  - Translations, circa 1968-1999, Subseries 2.7; Boxes 131-138; OP58-58a
    The subseries consists of both published and unpublished manuscripts and typescripts of translations from 1968-1999. Because of Hughes' propensity to reuse paper, cross-references are used to note locations of related materials in other parts of the collection.
    Arranged in chronological order by date of publication; undated works at the beginning of the subseries.
    - Gobello
    - Translation of a fragment from a rejected canto by Gabello [Acc. 1999-01-04] (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Translations of Ferene Juhasz
    - "The Boy Changed Into a Stag Cries Out at the Gate of Secrets," TS Translation of Juhasz poem [See also Subseries 2.3: "Crow Goes to the Movie;" Subseries 2.5: A Bedtime Story, MS; and Subseries 2.6: The Iron Man, MS] (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - Federico García Lorca Poems
    - "El agua del mar" [See also Subseries 2.7: Federico García Lorca Poems, "Lagarto viejo"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "El concierto interrumpido" [See also Subseries 2.7: Federico García Lorca Poems, "Lagarto viejo"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Lagarto viejo" (Box 131, Folder 3)
    - "Poema de la Saeta" [See also Subseries 2.7: Federico García Lorca Poems, "Lagarto viejo"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - Unidentified Federico García Lorca poem (Box 131, Folder 4)
    - Lorenzo de Medici (Il Magnifico)
    - Correspondence w/ Gaia Servadio re: translation of Lorenzo il Magnifico (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Poems, Yehuda Amichai (1968)
    - "Two Songs of Peace," TS (Box 131, Folder 6)
    - Assorted copies and translations by Assia Gutman for Poems (1968) (Box 131, Folder 7)
    - "Poetry of Yehuda Amichai" essay by Arieh Sachs for Judiasm: A Quarterly Journal of Jewish Life and Thought, vol. 14, no. 4, Fall Issue, 1965 (Box 131, Folder 8)
    - Time, Yehuda Amichai (1968)
    - Time, MS (photocopy of MS in Amichai's handwriting) (Box 131, Folder 9)
    - Time, TS (Box 131, Folder 10)
    - "A Weeping Mouth and a Laughing Mouth," TS (Box 131, Folder 11)
    - Vasko Popa: Selected Poems (1969)
    - Introduction, MS [See also Subseries 2.3: "The sea, in hearing"] (Box 131, Folder 12)
    - Seneca's Oedipus (1972)
    - Notes for Seneca's Oedipus (Box 131, Folder 13)
    - Seneca's Oedipus, TS (Box 131, Folder 14)
    - Seneca's Oedipus, Proofs (Box 131, Folder 15)
    - Janos Pilinszky: Selected Poems 1940-1976 (1976)
    - "Agonia Christina," TS (Box 131, Folder 16)
    - "Apocrypha," MS and TS (Box 131, Folder 17)
    - "Aquarium," MS and TS (Box 131, Folder 18)
    - "As I Was," MS and TS (Box 131, Folder 19)
    - "Big City Icons," MS and TS (Box 131, Folder 20)
    - "By the Time You Come," MS and TS (Box 131, Folder 21)
    - "Cold World," MS and TS (Box 131, Folder 22)
    - "Cold Wind," TS (Box 131, Folder 23)
    - "Complaint," MS and TS (Box 131, Folder 24)
    - "Crater," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Moortown, "Dead, she became space-earth] (Box 131, Folder 25)
    - "Crime and Punishment," MS and TS (Box 131, Folder 26)
    - "Desert of Love," MS and TS (Box 131, Folder 27)
    - "Enough," MS and TS (Box 131, Folder 28)
    - "Epilogue," MS and TS (Box 131, Folder 29)
    - "Exhortation," MS and TS (Box 131, Folder 30)
    - "Fable," MS and TS (Box 131, Folder 31)
    - "Fishes in the Net," MS and TS (Box 131, Folder 32)